A Guide to the Population Council records, International Programs, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 13 FA1433
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council records, International Programs, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 13
1963-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council
FA1433
17.05 Cubic Feet 29 legal-size document boxes and 9 letter-size document boxes.
Arrangement
Series 13: International Programs is arranged in the following subseries:
Subseries 1: Infant Feeding Study
Subseries 2: Field Staff File
Subseries 3: Routine Administration and Lippes Loops Files
Within each subseries the records remain in original order.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Personnel files are restricted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Records document the Population Council's International Programs (IP), and an earlier incarnation - the Technical Assistance Division, primarily focusing in the areas of the Infant Feeding Study and Lippes Loops. Records include but are not limited to: program files and reviews, proposals, reports, surveys, site visits, field reports, articles, field staff correspondence, general administrative records, and a small selection of donor files.
Biographical / Historical
The Population Council was founded by John D. Rockefeller 3rd in 1952 to undertake "significant activities in the broad field of population." Its goal has been to bring about a reduction in the number of births that occur in the world. In its early years, the business of the Population Council was conducted by a Demographic Division and a Biomedical Division. Through its Demographic Division, the Council sought to document what it conceived to be an overpopulation problem threatening many areas of the world. To accomplish this purpose, the Division facilitated research on the economic, social, and psychological factors which affect the growth and decline of human population. This Council-assisted research effort was conducted not only by staff of the Demographic Division but also by other institutions and scholars, some of whom received Council grants and fellowships and some of whom received informal advice and consultation on how to design and execute studies.
The Biomedical Division, which, beginning in 1959, occupied a laboratory at The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), has conducted pure and applied research on plant, animal, and human reproductive physiology and on the development, the physiological action, and the safety and effectiveness of contraceptive methods. The Council facilitated similar types of medical research by non-Council scientists at other institutions by giving grants and fellowships for such research. The Council's biomedical research and its support for research by non-Council scientists were instrumental in the development of the modern intrauterine coil and the birth control pill.
In about 1960, the scope of Population Council activities expanded. The Council began to render practical and technical aid to foreign nations. Beginning in that year, the Demographic Division, in addition to supervising research, became involved in Pakistan's family planning program, extending practical and technical aid in organizing and running a national family planning program. By 1964 the Council's Demographic Division had assisted in organizing family planning programs in South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, Tunisia, and Turkey. In that year, the Council created the Technical Assistance Division. This division, in ensuing years, continued the assistance of the Council in the countries where it had already become involved and also helped start and run programs in India, Morocco, the Philippines, and Puerto Rico.
An underlying aim of the Council's grant programs has been to encourage the development and growth of institutions that would promote family planning programs. To this end, the Council has given grants and advice to various universities and research centers for starting and upgrading programs for demographic and biomedical training and research programs; has assisted the United Nations to set up and expand regional Demographic Training and Research Centres in Bombay, India, Santiago, Chile, and Cairo, Egypt; has worked with the Ford Foundation on family planning programs in Pakistan, India, and North Africa.
In addition to rendering technical aid and sponsoring research, the Council has undertaken several complementary public relations efforts. To reach the general populations of the United States and of foreign nations, Council officers have worked to inform the mass media about population issues and to encourage magazine articles, movies, and books dealing with population matters. Council officers and representatives have also made trips and prepared reports to convince various foreign government leaders of the importance and the desirability of promulgating family planning programs. In addition, Council officers participated in and helped organize and finance conferences for demographers and medical scientists active in population work.
The Population Council has obtained its financial support through large contributions. The Ford and Rockefeller Foundations and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund have been the principal institutional supporters of the Council. John D. Rockefeller 3rd has been the single most significant individual backer of the Council.
- International Programs, 1963-1986; 13
  - Infant Feeding Study, 1
    - Colombia - Code Book, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Colombia - Final Survey Instrument, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Indonesia - Code Book, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Indonesia - Final Report, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Indonesia - Final Survey Instrument (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Indonesia - Medical Infrastructure Survey - Final Instrument (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Indonesia - Report on Research Findings (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Indonesia - Technical Report, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Kenya - Final Report (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Kenya - Final Survey Instrument (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Kenya- Final Survey Instrument (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Kenya - Code Book, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Kenya - Papers and Publications, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Kenya - Technical Report, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
    - Thailand - Code Book, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Thailand - Code Book, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Thailand - Final Survey, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Thailand - Papers and Publications, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Thailand - Technical Report, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
    - African Medical and Research Foundation (AMREF) Report, 1982 November (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Colombia - Ethnography Report - Draft, 1982 June (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Indonesia - Final Survey Instrument, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Indonesia - Survey Instrument (English) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Indonesia - Medical Infrastructure Survey (English) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Thailand - Final Survey Instrument, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Colombia - Survey Instrument Final (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Infant Feeding Survey - Guidelines for Data Analysis, 1982 June (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Population Council-International Program - Working Paper No. 19 - The Determinants of Infant Feeding Practices: Preliminary Results of a Four Country Study, 1984 April (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Summary, 1986 January 31 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Nairobi Site Report to USAID, 1986 January (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Bangkok Site Report to USAID, 1986 January (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Bogota Site Report to USAID, 1986 January (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Semarang Site Report to USAID, 1986 January (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Core Questionnaire, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Kenya - Medical Infrastructure Survey - Final Instrument (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Kenya - Final Survey Instrument, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Standard File Code Book and Card 4A Variable Lists (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Infant Feeding Study - AID-DSAN - C-0211 - Collaborating Institutions Survey Instruments (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Colombia - Marketing - State of the Industry - Retail Segment, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Colombia - Marketing - State of the Industry - Government Segment, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Colombia - Marketing - State of the Industry - Industry Segment, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Colombia - Figure VII - Relationship of Market Factors (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Infant Feeding Study - AID Project Review Panel Meeting, 1981 April 9-10 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Indonesia - Marketing - Infant Formula Marketing Practices, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Thailand - Marketing - Industry, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Kenya - Marketing - Industry, Government, 1977-1984 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Kenya - Marketing - Industry, Government, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Colombia - Marketing - Health Sector, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Government Component - Training Session, 1981 July (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Technical Proposal - For Distribution, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - AID - RFP, 1979 July-August (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Infant Feeding Study - The International Breast Feeding Compendium, Vol. 2, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Complete Technical Proposal, 1979 August (Box 10, Folder 56-57)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Summary, 1979 September (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Design Outline, 1980 September (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Consumer Behavior Paper, 1980 June (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - State of the Industry - Retail Market Paper, 1980 June (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Review Panel Project Documents, 1980 September (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Review Panel Project - Addendum Documents, 1980 September (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Questionnaire Manual, 1980 September (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Colombia Proposal - Javeriana University, 1980 December (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Conceptual Framework Paper, 1981 February (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Colombia - Site Visit Report - Marketing Report, 1981 February (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Ethnographic Field Manual (Revised), 1981 February (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Economic Model, 1981 February (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - AID Panel Binder Addendum, 1981 April (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Background and Conceptual Framework, 1981 April (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Questionnaire Manual, 1981 April (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Indonesia Proposal, Diponegoro University, 1981 March (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - Indonesia - Site Visit Report - Marketing Component, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Thailand Proposal, Mahidol University, 1981 March (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Thailand - Site Visit Report - Marketing Component, 1981 April (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - Kenya Proposal, Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS) and African Medical and Research Foundation (AMREF), 1981 April (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Kenya - Site Visit Report - Marketing Component, 1981 May (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - Interim Progress Report, 1981 August (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Conceptual Framework Binder, 1981 July (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Core Questionnaire, 1981 August (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Site Visit Reports, 1981 August (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - Methodology for Marketing Studies (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Second Interim Progress Repor, 1981 July-December (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Site Visit Reports Binder, 1982 March (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Country Progress Reports Binder, 1982 March (Box 13, Folder 86)
    - Data Analysis Guidelines, 1982 June (Box 13, Folder 87)
    - Third Interim Progress Report, 1982 October (Box 13, Folder 88)
    - Site Visit Reports, 1982 October (Box 13, Folder 89)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Country Progress Reports, 1982 October (Box 13, Folder 90)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Country Survey Instruments, 1982 October (Box 13, Folder 91)
    - Bibliography of Infant Feeding Study Project Library, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Country Sample Designs, 1982 November (Box 14, Folder 93)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Strategies Proposal, 1982 December (Box 14, Folder 94)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Public Policy Guidelines, 1983 January (Box 14, Folder 95)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Progress and Future Plans, 1983 June (Box 14, Folder 96)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - RFP Continuation, 1983 July (Box 14, Folder 97)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Ford Foundation Proposal, 1983 October (Box 14, Folder 98)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Fourth Progress Report, 1982 July-1983 June (Box 14, Folder 99)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Rockefeller Foundation Proposal, 1983 October (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - Site Visit Reports, 1983 October (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - AID Revised Proposal, 1983 November (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - Infant Feeding Study - Document Originals - UNICEF Proposal (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - Thailand - Infant Feeding Practice in Bangkok, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - Thailand - Final Report - Infant Feeding Practices in Bangkok, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - Thailand - Ethnography, Phase 2, Volume 4 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Thailand - Infant Feeding Study in Bangkok, Volume 1, Phase 1, Methodology (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Thailand - Ethnography Study, Volume 2, Phase 1 (Box 15, Folder 108)
    - Infant Feeding Practice Study in Semarang Municipality, 1981-1983 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - Indonesia - Ethnography Study - Phase II (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - Indonesia - Marketing Study - Technical Report, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - Indonesia - Ethnography Study - Phase I - Semarang, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Indonesia - Infant Feeding Practice Study - Semarang - Annexes (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Indonesia - Infant Feeding Practice Study - Semarang - Cross-Sectional Survey (Box 16, Folder 114)
    - Colombia - Infant Feeding Study - Bogota (Box 16, Folder 115)
    - Colombia - Ethnography Study (Box 16, Folder 116-117)
    - Colombia - The Infant Food Industry in Bogota, 1982 December (Box 17, Folder 118)
    - Colombia - Papers and Publications - Romero, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 119)
  - Field Staff File, 2
    - Cain - Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 17, Folder 120-122)
    - Robinson - Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 17, Folder 123-125)
    - Robinson - Field Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - Robinson - Articles (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Robinson - Population and Development Planning, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 128)
    - Vallin - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 18, Folder 129-131)
    - Vallin - Field Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 132)
    - Vallin - Field Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 19, Folder 133)
    - Vallin - Articles, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 134-135)
    - Chen, Lincoln - Ford Foundation, Bangladesh, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 136-137)
    - Chen, Lincoln - Ford Foundation, Bangladesh, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 138)
    - Wana Field Staff - General, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 139)
    - Alam - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 140)
    - Alam - Field Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 141)
    - Buhler - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 142)
    - Buhler - Field Reports, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 143)
    - De Tray - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 144-145)
    - De Tray - Field Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 146)
    - De Tray - Articles (Box 21, Folder 147-148)
    - Hill - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 149-150)
    - Hill - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 151-152)
    - Hill - Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 153)
    - Hill - Articles, 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 154)
    - Hill - Appointment Letter, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 155)
    - Hill - Field Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 156)
    - Cain - Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 157)
    - West Africa - Regional Documentation, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 158)
    - Krotki - Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 159)
    - Krotki - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 160)
    - Loudis - Reports, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 161)
    - Loudis - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 162)
    - Fawcett - Articles, 1972-1975 (Box 23, Folder 163)
    - Fawcett - Field Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 164)
    - Fawcett - Trip Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 165)
    - Field Staff - General Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 23, Folder 166)
    - Joint Memos to Field Staff, 1972-1975 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    - Fawcett - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 24, Folder 168-170)
    - Moir - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 171-172)
    - Moir - Field Reports, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 173)
    - Moir - Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 174)
    - Parsons - Correspondence and Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 175)
    - Speare - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 176-177)
    - Speare - Articles, 1973-1978 (Box 26, Folder 178)
    - Speare - Field Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 179)
    - Cernada - Taiwan, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 180)
    - Keeny - Taiwan, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 181)
    - Thailand - Correspondence, Reports, Studies, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 182)
    - Donaldson - Thailand, 1973-1976 (Box 26, Folder 183)
    - Robinson - Thailand, 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 184)
    - Wright - Thailand, 1973-1976 (Box 26, Folder 185)
  - Routine Administration and Lippes Loops Files, 3
    - Filing Systems, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 186)
    - Brochure - The Population Council, 1971-1977 (Box 27, Folder 187)
    - Lists - Articles, 1974-1976 (Box 27, Folder 188)
    - Files Committee and Decisions, 1970-1976 (Box 27, Folder 189)
    - Current Publications Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 190)
    - Grants Computerization Project, 1972-1975 (Box 27, Folder 191)
    - Pease and Lemkin Files, 1973-1975 (Box 27, Folder 192)
    - Book Lists - Previous Book Lists - Sources, Notes and Galleys (Box 27, Folder 193)
    - Management, Information and Education, 1970-1972 (Box 27, Folder 194)
    - TAD - Journal Subscriptions, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 195)
    - TAD - Meetings, 1973-1976 (Box 27, Folder 196)
    - Chronicle of Events, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 197)
    - Population Council Film Library, 1971-1977 (Box 27, Folder 198)
    - Lippes Loops - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 199)
    - Bronnenkant Meeting, 1975 June 6 (Box 27, Folder 200)
    - Lippes Loops - Finishing Enterprises, Inc. - Purchase Orders (Box 28, Folder 201)
    - IUD Shipments (Box 28, Folder 202)
    - Lippes Loops - Population Council Policy, 1964-1978 (Box 28, Folder 203)
    - Lippes Loops - Population Council Internal Memos and Reports Relating to PC-Ortho, 1965-1974 (Box 28, Folder 204)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - General, 1963-1976 (Box 28, Folder 205)
    - Lippes Loops - PC-Ortho - Legal Correspondence (Re: Donahue), 1964-1976 (Box 28, Folder 206)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Chile, 1964-1970 (Box 28, Folder 207)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Colombia, 1970-1975 (Box 28, Folder 208)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Cuba, 1972-1976 (Box 28, Folder 209)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Denmark, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 210)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Ecuador, 1966-1973 (Box 29, Folder 211)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - England, 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 212)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Egypt, 1966-1971 (Box 29, Folder 213)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - El Salvador, 1964-1967 (Box 29, Folder 214)
    - Lippes Loops - PC-Ortho - Country Approvals, 1964-1973 (Box 29, Folder 215)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Fiji, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 216)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Germany, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 217)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Greece, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 218)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Hong Kong, 1964-1970 (Box 29, Folder 219)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - India, 1964-1969 (Box 29, Folder 220)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Iran, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 221)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Jamaica, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 222)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Jerusalem, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 223)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Kenya, 1966-1970 (Box 29, Folder 224)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Korea, 1964-1970 (Box 29, Folder 225)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Malaysia, 1966-1972 (Box 30, Folder 226)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Mexico, 1967-1976 (Box 30, Folder 227)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Morocco, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 228)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Nicaragua, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 229)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Nigeria, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 230)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Pakistan, 1964-1970 (Box 30, Folder 231)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Philippines, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 232)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Poland, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 233)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Sida, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 234)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Singapore, 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 235)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Sri Lanka, 1965-1968 (Box 30, Folder 236)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Tawain, 1964-1970 (Box 30, Folder 237)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Thailand, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 238)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Trinidad and Tobago, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 239)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Tunisia, 1964-1975 (Box 30, Folder 240)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Turkey, 1965-1975 (Box 30, Folder 241)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Union of South Africa, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 242)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - United States, 1964-1970 (Box 31, Folder 243)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - Venezuela, 1969-1975 (Box 31, Folder 244)
    - Lippes Loops - Licenses, Patents, Distribution, Manufacture (LPDM) - World Health Organization, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 245)
    - Inserters - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 246)
    - IUD Manufacturing Handbook, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 247)